ANATOLY YAKOVENKO

aeyakovenko@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software developer with over 10 years of experience in embedded operating systems, developing <u>patents</u>, leading projects and contributing to large groups including <u>Linux Kernel</u>, with a focus on performance and optimization for Qualcomm ARM and DSP processors.

SKILLS

Hardware and Systems

• Embedded Operating Systems, Linux Kernel, Android, Qualcomm MSMs, System MMUs, ARM, Hexagon DSP

Languages and Tools

• C, C++, Haskell, Lua, Make, Bash, Python, Ruby, Git, Perforce, GDB, Trace32

WORK EXPERIENCE

Qualcomm, San Diego CA

Senior Staff Engineer, 2012 to Present Staff Engineer, 2008 - 2012 Senior Engineer, 2006 - 2009 Engineer, 2003 - 2006

- Heterogenous Multicore Compute
 Lead development of FastRPC, a brand new technology featured in Hexagon SDK for
 off-loading computations between ARM and DSP co-processors on Qualcomm's mobile
 chips. Achieved a rox reduction in co-processor communication latency. Developed
 several patents, and commercialized on Android, Windows and Qnx. Extensive hands-on
 experience developing and debugging multi-core systems. Worked with internal and
 third party developers on power and performance optimizations on Computer Vision,
 Augmented Reality, and 3D Camera technologies utilizing Qualcomm's DSP.
- Mobile Operating Systems
 Lead development of Inter-Process Communication for BREW, Qualcomm's mobile
 operating system shipped on thousands of devices, and millions of units. Additionally
 developed frameworks, tools, and custom Interface Description Language compiler.
 Designed critical pieces of the kernel. Lead interface reviews with a focus on binary
 backwards compatibility, security, and performance.
- QChat Push To Talk
 Developed network components using SIP/HTTP/RTP and proprietary standards for
 QChat Push To Talk service. Designed high performance logging tools to handle tens of
 thousands of transactions per second from many networked components with a real time monitoring system.

Alescere LLC, Lisle IL

Co-Founder, 2001 to 2003

• Founding member of <u>Alescere</u>, a VOIP startup Lead development of SIP and <u>RTP</u> protocol stacks, and server components for a VoIP system for small businesses.

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Research Assistant, 2003

- Developed a web server that supports QoS for HTTP requests
- Designed a probabilistic scheduler for the Linux kernel
- Implemented a roaming protocol for 802.11a/b networks for NetBSD

Personal Research

 Neural Networks, Genetic Algorithms, Markov Models, and Bayesian Inference Algorithms

References

- Brian Kelley, Senior Director of Technology, bkelley@quicinc.com
- Rob Walker, Senior Director of Engineering, rwalker@quicinc.com
- Ramesh Chandrasekhar, Director of Engineering, rameshc@qti.qualcomm.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2003